<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joseph (Joe)  Manning | Sarkisov Research Group</title>
    <link>https://SarkisovTeam.github.io/group-website/author/joseph-joe-manning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://SarkisovTeam.github.io/group-website/author/joseph-joe-manning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Joseph (Joe)  Manning</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://SarkisovTeam.github.io/group-website/author/joseph-joe-manning/avatar_hub175f58039f63cba83a0793c189d37bf_1268756_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url>
      <title>Joseph (Joe)  Manning</title>
      <link>https://SarkisovTeam.github.io/group-website/author/joseph-joe-manning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digitally Reproducing MOF Material Synthesis Conditions For Quantitative Comparison</title>
      <link>https://SarkisovTeam.github.io/group-website/project/synthesis-digitisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SarkisovTeam.github.io/group-website/project/synthesis-digitisation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Metal organic framework (MOF) materials represent an exciting new development in porous materials science, with myriad applications in fields as diverse as carbon capture, catalysis, and water harvesting. 
However, with tens of thousands of MOF syntheses identified, reproducing a reported framework or identifying the best synthesis route is a complex and often frustrating task. 
Further, these syntheses are often reported as plain text, preventing quantitative comparison between different studies. 
In this research theme, we are applying text mining and natural language processing tools to digitise MOF synthesis methods. Using this depth-first text mining framework, we aim to perform optimisation of synthesis methods solely from pre-existing published data, accelerating methodology development and hence implementation of MOF materials in larger-scale applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screening Complex Adsorption Phenomena Using Advanced Monte Carlo Simulations</title>
      <link>https://SarkisovTeam.github.io/group-website/project/screening-complex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SarkisovTeam.github.io/group-website/project/screening-complex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Screening adsorption behaviour of porous materials is highly valuable to select candidates for scale-up and direct novel materials discovery. 
However, current methods are limited to adsorption of either very small ro simple molecules, unable to describe complex adsorption phenomena like water capture or arene isomer separation. 
We are developing methods to accelerate the estimation of adsorption properties for these complex material applications, enabling high-throughput screening for an ever-larger series of applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
